<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://alanxoc3.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://alanxoc3.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-03-07T21:51:31-07:00</updated><id>http://alanxoc3.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Alan Morgan</title><subtitle>Yet another guy's blog!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Kakoune vs Neovim</title><link href="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2021/03/07/kakoune-vs-neovim.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kakoune vs Neovim" /><published>2021-03-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-03-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://alanxoc3.github.io/2021/03/07/kakoune-vs-neovim</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2021/03/07/kakoune-vs-neovim.html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I mentioned that I started using Kakoune a few months ago in a
youtube thread. Someone then asked me what the differences are between Kakoune
and Neovim. I ended up writing a consideral amount of thoughts of the pros and
cons of Neovim vs Kakoune. So I’ll share that in a blog post too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kakoune is not for everyone, but here are some of the pros and cons for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;pros-of-kakoune-over-neovim&quot;&gt;Pros of Kakoune over Neovim&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, Kakoune follows the unix philosophy more closely than Neovim
does. For example, Kakoune doesn’t have multiple windows or floating windows.
Instead it encourages you to make use of your terminal multiplexer or window
manager. That can be seen as a drawback, but I see it as a benefit, since it
encourages more thought &amp;amp; development towards the editor experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kakoune is built with shell integration in mind. One way to demonstrate this is
that it doesn’t have much of a configuration language. To create any complex
logic or plugins for Kakoune, you have to write it in another language and
Kakoune will comunicate with it via environment variables and stdout. This
encourages people to write programs that can server both as useful unix
scripting utilities and also Kakoune plugins. I wish other editors followed a
similar pattern, because that promotes plugin authors to write programs that
could be useful to other editors or useful for scripting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kakoune does multiple cursors instead of visual selection or global search and
replace. In my experience so far, multiple cursors are much more fun than
global search and replace. I’m pretty sure they can do everything visual
selection can do. Plus they can do other cool things, like rotating all text
multiple cursor selections, which is something I don’t know if other IDE
multiple cursor implementations can handle. You can also filter through your
selections, which isn’t really a concept in vim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus there are a bunch of nice small things like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy shell integration with the pipe character, instead of the “:%!” thing in vim.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Macros default to one register, so just type “q” to playback your macro, instead of “@q”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modes outside of normal &amp;amp; insert have a menu that shows and describes keybindings. This makes it easy to add documentation for user and plugin keybindings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a built in keybinding for inserting a blank line (alt+o). That’s something I had to create myself in Neovim because I noticed I was typing “o&lt;esc&gt;k&quot; too much.&lt;/esc&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kakoune uses standard regex, instead of vim’s specific regex format that I always forget.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generally, the default editor keybindings in Kakoune are somewhat similar to Neovim’s, but much more thoughtout. Neovim can’t do this, because they aim to be fully compatible with vi/vim out of the box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;pros-of-neovim-over-kakoune&quot;&gt;Pros of Neovim over Kakoune&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neovim has a lot more plugins than Kakoune, because there are far more users.
Just looking at stars on github, Neovim has almost 6 times more stars than
Kakoune. Plugin management is also more difficult with Kakoune, because plugins
tend to be written in different languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kakoune doesn’t handly formatting or indentation well, at least not out of the
box. The idea is that you should let an external command help you format things
that are specific to your file. But that doesn’t apply to every file format.
Neovim sometimes guesses what tab should do based on context or the file
format, which sometimes seems magic to me, but it’s usually nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neovim is starting to support treesitter, which Kakoune doesn’t support at all.
Kakoune’s regex highlighting also doesn’t feel as mature as Neovim’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also having some problems getting some of Kakoune’s keybindings working
with terminal emulators on my Macbook. I had to switch from Alacritty to Kitty
to get this working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like the philosophy behind Kakoune, which is what intrigued me enough to make
an editor switch. In practice, Neovim’s large plugin library makes up for the
less eficient keybindings that Kakoune proposes, but hopefully Kakoune will
acquire more plugins and features in time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="code" /><summary type="html">Yesterday, I mentioned that I started using Kakoune a few months ago in a youtube thread. Someone then asked me what the differences are between Kakoune and Neovim. I ended up writing a consideral amount of thoughts of the pros and cons of Neovim vs Kakoune. So I’ll share that in a blog post too!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mr. Crocodile’s Pond.</title><link href="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2020/01/06/mr-crocodiles-pond.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mr. Crocodile's Pond." /><published>2020-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://alanxoc3.github.io/2020/01/06/mr-crocodiles-pond</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2020/01/06/mr-crocodiles-pond.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I made a story with my girlfriend the other day. And now, I want to share it
here in my blog! We made the story by taking turns writing a sentence or two.
This is the story after a bit of editing to make it more presentable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a dark night long ago, and the little giraffe was all alone. He wanted to drink
water but he was too scared to go to the river by himself. Then a crocodile
came up to him and said, “It’s okay little giraffe, I know the river very well,
I can take you there.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The giraffe responded, “Really? You are a really good person. Thanks for
offering, but I don’t think I’ll actually get water tonight, since it’s so
dark. Take care Mr. Crocodile!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-child&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;/res/img/croc-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A picture.&quot; class=&quot;rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crocodile replied, “Alright, but I’ll be back, and if you are ever thirsty
in the future, just let me know!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, the giraffe felt a little angry, “So you are just gonna leave me
here all alone?” He continued, “I thought you were my friend!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Crocodile said, “You don’t need my help right now, so why should I help
you? I’ll just find another lonely animal to help.” The giraffe said, “Well,
can I just go with you to find another lonely animal. I can take you to my
sister. She might be lonely. And you might like her.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Crocodile responded, “Okay, how about in the morning, we both go to your
sister and take her to the river together.” The giraffe agreed, so the two
slept and departed to the giraffe’s sister’s house in the morning. The
giraffe’s sister was no ordinary giraffe, because she was actually a deer. Her
name was Jennie the deer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon meeting Jennie, Mr. Crocodile exclaimed, “Oh dear, what a beautiful dear!”
Mr. Crocodile asked Jennie, “How are you this fine morning, would you care to
travel to the river with us to get a drink?” Mr. Crocodile tried to pose a
handsome posture as he was saying this. However Jennie the deer said, “I would
join you to the river but I don’t drink polluted river water. I only drink pure
rain water. Can you find that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The giraffe told Jennie, “Oh, don’t worry Jennie, Mr. Crocodile knows the river
very well, I’m sure he can find some of that water there!” Mr. Crocodile agreed
and said, “That’s right, there is a special pond near the river that contains
only rainwater. Let’s head over there now!” So the three of them, the giraffe,
the crocodile, and the deer, took off to the pond!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-child&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;/res/img/croc-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A picture.&quot; class=&quot;rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey to the pond was longer than going to the river. It took 3 whole
days to get there. The three of them were hungry and thirsty, but knew that the
pond would be worth the wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they were walking, Mr. Crocodile and Jennie the deer were thinking of each
other. Mr. Crocodile was thinking, “Stupid deer. She is so annoying, but she
looks so delicious. Much more delicious than the giraffe. However, women are
trouble no matter what their age is or what species they are. I just want to
eat and that tasty deer. I need to find that pond first though. How do I get
there again? Let me think.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And deer’s thoughts about the crocodile were, “Stupid crocodile. He is so
innocent, thinking he can help me. I know he likes me, but once we get to the
rainwater pond, I’ll break his heart and make him leave. Then I will have all
the water to myself. Hahaha!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they were continuing their journey, they found a pond on the fourth day. It
wasn’t the same pond the crocodile had in mind, but Mr. Crocodile still
exclaimed, “Umm. Uh. Look! This is the special water we were looking for!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jennie was really happy because Mr. Crocodile brought her to a pond. The little
giraffe jumped into the pond and shouted, “Come here Jennie, it’s really
comfortable inside!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for both of them, Mr. Crocodile finally had them trapped. The
giraffe or the deer, which one should he eat first? Mr. Crocodile decided to go
after Jennie, since she looked more delicious than the giraffe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jennie thought she was using Mr. Crocodile, after all, she was a beautiful
deer. But now she was Mr. Crocodile’s prey. As Mr. Crocodile was straddling
towards her, she shouted, “Wait, Mr. Crocodile, don’t you remember how happy we
used to be together?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Crocodile said, “I was never happy around you. Goodbye Jennie the deer!”
And with that, he swallowed the deer whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The little giraffe was confused and didn’t understand what just happened to his
sister. He thought that Mr. Crocodile was his friend. The giraffe realized that
the crocodile wanted to eat him. The giraffe cried, “I am a friend, please.”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-child&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;/res/img/croc-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A picture.&quot; class=&quot;rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Crocodile interrupted saying, “Stupid giraffe, you shouldn’t trust creepy
crocodiles. It’s your fault the deer is dead, and now I’ll eat y…?!??!?!” But
as he was finishing his sentence, he started chocking on the deer’s antlers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many years later, after the giraffe became big, the big giraffe was telling a
story between a little giraffe, a deer, and a crocodile to his child. “It was a
dark night long ago…” The little giraffe said, “Daddy, so we shouldn’t trust
crocodiles, right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big giraffe said, “Yes son, only stupid giraffes trust creepy crocodiles
and think their sister is a deer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fin.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="story" /><summary type="html">I made a story with my girlfriend the other day. And now, I want to share it here in my blog! We made the story by taking turns writing a sentence or two. This is the story after a bit of editing to make it more presentable.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Diomedes.</title><link href="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2020/01/05/diomedes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Diomedes." /><published>2020-01-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-01-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://alanxoc3.github.io/2020/01/05/diomedes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2020/01/05/diomedes.html">&lt;p&gt;Diomedes is one of the most important characters in the Illiad, but I had never
heard of him until I started reading the book. Diomedes is super important in
the first half of the Illiad, whereas Achilles doesn’t make much of an
appearance until the last quarter of the book. Diomedes is regarded by the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Names_of_the_Greeks&quot;&gt;Achaeans&lt;/a&gt; as the most
powerful warrior among them all, second only to Achilles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diomedes had a few cool experiences. One of them was that he injured 2 gods,
Aphrodite and Ares. Diomedes was about to kill
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aeneas&quot;&gt;Aeneas&lt;/a&gt;, but Aphrodite saved him, since
he was her son. Diomedes chased after Aphrodite and injured her. Apollo then
saved Both Aphrodite and Aeneas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit later, as Ares leads the Trojan forces, Diomedes stays back because
Athena told him to not attack gods. When Athena finds Diomedes not fighting,
she asks him why. Diomedes replies that Ares is with them and he is only
following her orders. Athena then tells Diomedes not to be afraid of Ares, and
she will attack him with her. So they injure Ares together, causing Ares to
complain to Zeus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only was Diomedes a powerful warrior, but he was also humble, intelligent,
and courageous. When Agamemnon wanted to consider retreat in the middle of the
book, Diomedes encouraged him to go and encourage fighting soldiers with him
instead. At the beginning of the book, Agamemnon taunted Diomedes, saying that
his father was a much better fighter than him, however Diomedes didn’t take
offense. Diomedes understood that Agamemnon was really just trying to urge him
to fight hard. When Agamemnon said something similar to Odysseus, Odysseus was
very angry. Odysseus is much more well known, because of the Odyssey, but
Diomedes seems like a super interesting person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another incident Diomedes has is that he meets a warrior on the Trojan side
named Glaucus. Diomedes considers Glaucus to be very brave, so they talk to
each other and find out their ancestors were acquaintances, so they decided to
swap armor instead of fight. Diomedes gave Glaucus bronze armor, while Glaucus
gave Diomedes gold armor. According to Wikipedia, this is where the term
‘Diomedian Swap’ comes from. So Diomedes made his way to an obscure saying in
English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diomedes would have killed Hector twice, if Hector wasn’t protected by the
gods. Diomedes was visited by Athena many times and given temporary power to
see gods. Diomedes also had a stealth mission with Odysseus, going into the
Trojan camp by night, killing tons of
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thracians&quot;&gt;Thracians&lt;/a&gt;, stealing horses, and
obtaining information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, the point of this post is to talk about how underrated of a
character Diomedes is in The Illiad. Unfortunately, my first experience to the
Illiad was watching the movie “Troy” with Brad Pitt. I saw it with some
roommates a few years ago who all loved the move and believed it to be accurate
to the book. The movie didn’t even have Diomedes, one of the most important
characters, in it. I would never recommend
“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bustle.com/articles/24095-troy-turns-10-why-im-still-mad-at-period-epic-and-brad-pitts-hair-isnt-the&quot;&gt;Troy&lt;/a&gt;”
to anyone. You should definitely read the book. The book is full of gods
interacting with humans, the in-escapability of fate, and constant plot twists
in every chapter. I wouldn’t consider the movie to have any of those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve wanted to write about Diomedes for a while, because I think he is really
cool. I finally did it, thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="homer" /><summary type="html">Diomedes is one of the most important characters in the Illiad, but I had never heard of him until I started reading the book. Diomedes is super important in the first half of the Illiad, whereas Achilles doesn’t make much of an appearance until the last quarter of the book. Diomedes is regarded by the Achaeans as the most powerful warrior among them all, second only to Achilles.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Illiad, Shurrupak, and Virtue Theory.</title><link href="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/08/18/the-illiad-shurrupak-and-virtue-theory.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Illiad, Shurrupak, and Virtue Theory." /><published>2019-08-18T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-08-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/08/18/the-illiad-shurrupak-and-virtue-theory</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/08/18/the-illiad-shurrupak-and-virtue-theory.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s the weekend and I had some time with myself today, so I decided to just
research things. Today I read the first 2 books of “The Illiad”, along with
small translations of some of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/news/what-is-the-oldest-known-piece-of-literature&quot;&gt;earliest known written texts of
mankind&lt;/a&gt;:
“The Kesh Temple Hymn” and “The Instructions of Shuruppak”. Afterwards, I
watched a Crash Course video on “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sWppk7-Mti4&quot;&gt;The Epic of
Gilgamesh&lt;/a&gt;”. Followed by moral
theory Crash Course videos, concluding with Aristotle’s “Virtue Theory”. I’ll
share and relate my study, hoping that you as the reader may be able to benefit
from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Iliad&quot;&gt;The Illiad&lt;/a&gt;”,
this story takes place towards the end of the Trojan war. Achilles and
Agamemnon are two very important figures on the Greek side of the war. Achilles
is regarded as the strongest soldier, while Agamemnon is King and therefore the
most powerful person overall. Achilles stands up to Agamemnon and as a result
Agamemnon takes Achilles’ concubine for himself. To me, it seems like this is
done partly out of greed and also revenge. Achilles rants to his goddess mom
Thetis, telling her to ask Jupiter to let the Greeks suffer at the hand of the
Trojans, so that the Greeks, most notably Agamemnon, will realize how much they
actually need Achilles’ help. His mom does end up asking Jupiter and Jupiter
hesitantly agrees. Jupiter is hesitant, because his wife Juno thinks he is
already siding with the Trojans, even though he is really trying to take a
neutral stance. It seems like Jupiter had a difficult job, because he had to
try to satisfy the opinions and views of many different Gods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Wikipedia article on the Illiad, it mentions the topic of Bicameralism.
According to the article, Bicameralism states that humans at this earlier time
period lacked a concious and that most of the actions in the Illiad were
influenced by a God. I feel like the act of Achilles telling his mom to talk to
Zeus would be one of the exceptions to that last assertion. Though my claim
could be under fallacy of mistranslation of the version of the Illiad I am
reading, Achilles’ wishful revenge does seems to have a major part in the
story, so I’m guessing it is not a mistranslation, I would need more research
back this up though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to fulfil his promise, Jupiter sent a dream to Agamemnon saying the
Greeks should seize Troy, Jupiter knowing it would not go very well for the
Greeks. I thought it was very interesting and different to see the degree of
obedience in which the provincial kings were loyal to a seemingly irrational
Agamemnon. Especially Nestor and Ulysses, some of the most rational characters
in the story thus far, were extremely loyal to Agamemnon, to the point of
correcting rebellious soldiers (e.g. Thersitus).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was my extent of reading the Illiad today. The Illiad is one of the
earliest epics in human history, but the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Iliad&quot;&gt;Epic of
Gilgamesh&lt;/a&gt; definitely
predates it by a significant amount of time. Though Gilgamesh predates the
Illiad, it has not been relevant to much of Western civilization, because of
the fact that it wasn’t available until more recent archaeological finds.
Though even if it was available before the mid 1800s, Hellenistic and Roman
culture has seemed to overshadow much of other ancient cultures during the
progress of Western civilization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://etcsl.orinst.ox.ac.uk/section5/tr561.htm&quot;&gt;The Instructions of
Shuruppak&lt;/a&gt;” is a very short
and interesting read. It is a short text, in which a man named “Curuppag” is
giving moral advice, or wisdom, to his son “Zi-ud-sura”. I could have the wrong
understanding, but I get the impression that the “Bicameralism” I mentioned
earlier doesn’t apply to this text, and this text marginally predates the
Illiad. Some of the moral suggestions include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t have sex with a slave girl, prostitute, or another man’s wife.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“A loving heart maintains a family; a hateful heart destroys a family.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be careful about your actions when you are drunk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t travel at night.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be submissive to people with more authority than you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://etcsl.orinst.ox.ac.uk/section5/tr561.htm&quot;&gt;The Kesh Temple Hymn&lt;/a&gt;” on
the other hand was more bland. It mentions 8 (or 9) buildings/temples/houses
that could be part of a new town. Each house is described to be pretty
magnificent, relating to the glory of some specific Gods, especially “Akgi”,
“Nintud” and “Kec”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished my study with some moral philosophy overview. Watching from Crash
Course is by no means a primary source (Wikipedia isn’t either), but I can
relay my interpretation of each moral theory here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divine Command Theory: Morality comes from supernatural being(s).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Natural Law Theory: Aquinas says God made us with morals, we just need to
keep them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kant’s Theory: Never break your morals, even if it seems like breaking them
would be the correct decision.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Utilitarianism: Do the most good for the most people.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contractarianism: Morals only come from society/government, because it is
generally beneficial to humans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PrvtOWEXDIQ&quot;&gt;Virtue Theory&lt;/a&gt;: There are
really good people who understand how to be human. Try to be a good person
and try to become one of those people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtue theory was the last in the unit, and it also resonates the most with me.
Maybe coming from a Christian background, thinking Jesus Christ is one of those
virtuous people I want to try to emulate. Or maybe because virtue theory is a
Greek idea and my study today focused on a Greek epic. I wonder if the
Mesopotamians had a similar concept with “Virtue Theory”. The Bicameralism view
would probably argue no, but “The Instructions of Shurrupak” do show that
wisdom was passed down to later generations even at a very early stage in
recorded history. Also the character of Nestor and Ulysses in the Illiad seem
to resonate with a sense of this virtue, because they seem to be mature enough
to deal with problems and please different parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I’ve tied up my studies for today. Hopefully you found this useful. I’ll
try to make more posts like this in the future, whether it is about
Philosophy/Great Books, or about something more technical. While I’m sharing
knowledge with the world, I am also reinforcing my own learning, so that’s a
plus! Hope you enjoyed this :).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="homer" /><category term="philosophy" /><summary type="html">It’s the weekend and I had some time with myself today, so I decided to just research things. Today I read the first 2 books of “The Illiad”, along with small translations of some of the earliest known written texts of mankind: “The Kesh Temple Hymn” and “The Instructions of Shuruppak”. Afterwards, I watched a Crash Course video on “The Epic of Gilgamesh”. Followed by moral theory Crash Course videos, concluding with Aristotle’s “Virtue Theory”. I’ll share and relate my study, hoping that you as the reader may be able to benefit from it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A brave little netbook.</title><link href="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/30/a-brave-little-netbook.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A brave little netbook." /><published>2019-06-30T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-06-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/30/a-brave-little-netbook</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/30/a-brave-little-netbook.html">&lt;p&gt;I survived most of college and eventually earned my Computer Science degree
with only a little &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asus.com/us/Laptops/ASUS_EeeBook_X205TA/&quot;&gt;ASUS
x205ta&lt;/a&gt; netbook. This
computer has been reliable with me and served me well throughout the past 4
years. When I first bought the computer in 2015, I was mainly looking for
something cheap with a good battery life. The main specs taken from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asus.com/us/Laptops/ASUS_EeeBook_X205TA/specifications/&quot;&gt;ASUS
website&lt;/a&gt;
are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quad core 1.33 GHz Processor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 GB RAM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;32 GB eMMC Storage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1366x768 px Display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reviews online for this computer were mostly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laptopmag.com/reviews/laptops/asus-eeebook-x205ta&quot;&gt;very
good&lt;/a&gt;, compared
to other netbooks, so I felt very confident about my decision to make the
purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved the look and feel of my computer as soon as I received it. But to make
it usable I had to immediately replace Windows with
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;. I was able to get through the tricky
32-bit EFI installation, but ASUS proprietary drivers left my computer with
many problems including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The speaker, microphone, and headphone jack didn’t work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most of the Fn keys didn’t work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The multi-touch features for the trackpad were buggy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bluetooth didn’t work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The computer couldn’t hibernate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And random freezes occured after extended use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t give up on my brave little netbook though! After 2 years, the Linux
community was able to solve most of the x205ta problems listed above. The main
problem remaining was that the audio still didn’t work. I temporarilly solved
this by always using an external USB audio jack with headphones. Eventually
audio did make progress in a historic x205ta &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.kernel.org/show_bug.cgi?id=95681&quot;&gt;bugzilla
thread&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubuntuforums.org/showthread.php?t=2254322&amp;amp;page=125&amp;amp;p=13591881#post13591881&quot;&gt;Ubuntu forum
post&lt;/a&gt;.
Today, every driver issue has been fixed and integrated into modern kernel
builds. My only contribution to the x205ta Linux movement was a few edits on
the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/ASUS_x205ta&quot;&gt;Arch x205ta Wiki&lt;/a&gt;
though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s been four years. I’ve been through a lot with this netbook and it will
be hard to part with it. That aside, it will have to be done. I’m ready for
something new. I will have to say goodbye to the familiar and embrace the
unfamiliar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or I could just buy the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asus.com/us/Laptops/ASUS-Laptop-E203MA/&quot;&gt;newer
model&lt;/a&gt; of it with improved
specs :D.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="code" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html">I survived most of college and eventually earned my Computer Science degree with only a little ASUS x205ta netbook. This computer has been reliable with me and served me well throughout the past 4 years. When I first bought the computer in 2015, I was mainly looking for something cheap with a good battery life. The main specs taken from the ASUS website are: Quad core 1.33 GHz Processor 2 GB RAM 32 GB eMMC Storage 1366x768 px Display</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Binaries done right with git.</title><link href="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/29/binaries-done-right-with-git.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Binaries done right with git." /><published>2019-06-29T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-06-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/29/binaries-done-right-with-git</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/29/binaries-done-right-with-git.html">&lt;p&gt;The past few days, I dedicated some time to studying about how to use git
better and how some of the git internals work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My study started because of creating this very &lt;a href=&quot;http://alanxoc3.github.io&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;. To ease
the creation of blog posts and maintaining the website, I wanted to store all
my images in the same GitHub repository. But I knew there is an inherent
problem with this. Git saves the history of every commit. If I edit and commit
one of the images contained in my blog’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alanxoc3/alanxoc3.github.io&quot;&gt;GitHub
repository&lt;/a&gt;, git will still
store the previous unneeded version in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.git&lt;/code&gt; folder. Although I probably
won’t edit enough binary files for this to be a big problem, it is still a
minor problem for a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Large unused git objects (blobs) will waste space on my &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/06/30/a-brave-little-netbook.html&quot;&gt;little netbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clone/Push/Pull times could be slower.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I wanna know if there is a better way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few google searches, I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-lfs.github.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git-lfs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Here
is the description taken from the website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Git Large File Storage (LFS) replaces large files such as audio samples,
videos, datasets, and graphics with text pointers inside Git, while storing
the file contents on a remote server like GitHub.com or GitHub Enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool! This takes away version control for my large binary files, but keeps them
in git, for GitHub to accept. That’s exactly what I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The install is straightforward for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archlinux.org/packages/community/x86_64/git-lfs/&quot;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt;. After
installing, it’s really easy to set up for a &lt;strong&gt;brand new repository&lt;/strong&gt;. Check
out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-lfs.github.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait!!!! &lt;strong&gt;I don’t have a brand new repository.&lt;/strong&gt; And my repository already has
a bunch of binary files. What can I do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry anxious reader, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git-lfs v2.2.1&lt;/code&gt; or later makes it really easy to
migrate a repository! After running a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git lfs install&lt;/code&gt; on the repo, use this
script taken from one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/git-lfs/git-lfs/wiki/Tutorial#migrating-existing-repository-data-to-lfs&quot;&gt;official
tutorials&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;git lfs migrate import &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--include&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;*.png&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--include-ref&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;refs/heads/master &lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--include-ref&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;refs/heads/other_branch&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: You should replace &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;png&lt;/code&gt; with your file extension of choice (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;png&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jpg&lt;/code&gt;,
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mp3&lt;/code&gt;, etc). And each &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--include-ref&lt;/code&gt; line should correspond to each branch on
your server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, run a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git lfs ls-files&lt;/code&gt; to see if your existing files are stored
by &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git-lfs&lt;/code&gt;. If they are, then you are good to go my kind sir :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh wait, no you’re not. Remember that you will need to run a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git push
--force&lt;/code&gt;, since you are going to rewrite history on your git host server. Don’t
you just love rewriting history?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;. Even though the idea of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git-lfs&lt;/code&gt; is cool, after trying to make
it work for my GitHub blog, I found out that GitHub Pages &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/github/pages-gem/issues/515&quot;&gt;doesn’t support&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git-lfs&lt;/code&gt;! I guess I will have to revert my hard work and
go back to using just plain git for now. I’ll edit this post if GitHub Pages
ever supports &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git-lfs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what I had to share for today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="code" /><category term="git" /><summary type="html">The past few days, I dedicated some time to studying about how to use git better and how some of the git internals work.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What if we reversed asteroids?</title><link href="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/26/what-if-we-reversed-asteroids.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What if we reversed asteroids?" /><published>2019-06-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-06-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/26/what-if-we-reversed-asteroids</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/26/what-if-we-reversed-asteroids.html">&lt;p&gt;The winter of 2016. Too cold to go outside. Ice and snow everywhere. A poor
college student. A bored college student. A trapped college student. What can
he do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I know, he can make a game!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student asks roomie, “Hey roomie, I wanna make a game. Do ya got, any good
ideas for me?” Roomie replies, “Blah blah &lt;strong&gt;REVERSE ASTEROIDS&lt;/strong&gt; blah blah.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thus &lt;strong&gt;Revast&lt;/strong&gt; was born!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the coolest parts of this project was making the AI for the ship in the
player vs computer mode. Though you can beat the AI pretty easily if you circle
the screen, I hadn’t created an AI that complex before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other cool part was that I programmed part of this game while being stuck
on a bus in the middle of a blizzard :D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is a few years old, but I have gotten better at game development,
so maybe I will improve it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, here it is, an asteroids game where you can control the
asteroids!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-child&quot;&gt;
   &lt;iframe class=&quot;pico8-iframe&quot; src=&quot;/res/carts/revast.html&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
   &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="pico-8" /><category term="game" /><summary type="html">The winter of 2016. Too cold to go outside. Ice and snow everywhere. A poor college student. A bored college student. A trapped college student. What can he do?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">More efficient sprite outlines.</title><link href="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/25/efficient-pico-8-outline.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="More efficient sprite outlines." /><published>2019-06-25T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-06-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/25/efficient-pico-8-outline</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/25/efficient-pico-8-outline.html">&lt;p&gt;“How do I make a sprite have an outline in Pico-8?” I wondered. That question
lead me to find this
&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/Liquidream/1b419261dc324708f008f24ee6d13d7b&quot;&gt;algorithm&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;- Change the color palette to one color.
- Draw the sprite 8 times at these positions:
   - x-1 , y-1
   - x   , y-1
   - x+1 , y-1
   - x+1 , y
   - x+1 , y+1
   - x   , y+1
   - x-1 , y+1
   - x-1 , y
- Reset the palette color.
- Draw the sprite one last time at `x,y`.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Months passed by, and I was content with that approach. Until I ran into CPU
efficiency concerns. I need to do something differently. So I came up with a
different algorithm using sprite scaling:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;- Change the color palette to one color.
- Draw the sprite about 2-4 pixels larger than normal.
- Reset the palette color.
- Draw the sprite again, but with a normal size.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While that algorithm is much more efficient and kind-of cool, the outline looks
really ugly. It was at this point that I decided to just draw sprite outlines
in the sprite sheet itself. It resulted in some 10x10 sprites and looked like
this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-child&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;/res/img/efficient_outline.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture.&quot; class=&quot;rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The upsides:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My program is more efficient.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m using less tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The downsides:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m wasting sprite space by keeping the outlines in the sprite sheet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I wanted to have more sprite space. So I went back to thinking of
algorithms, and I was able to come up with a new algorithm using rectangles!
Here it is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;- For each column in the sprite.
   - Save the x &amp;amp; y for both the top &amp;amp; bottom pixels.
- Cache all those coordinates for future use.
- Draw a rectangle for each column.
- Draw the sprite.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I was pretty proud of that idea. The code ended up being a bit more
complex due to edge cases, but it isn’t too bad. You can see it on the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lexaloffle.com/bbs/?tid=32996&quot;&gt;lexaloffle post&lt;/a&gt;. You can also try
out the demo here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-child&quot;&gt;
   &lt;iframe class=&quot;pico8-iframe&quot; src=&quot;/res/carts/efficient_outline.html&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
   &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This algorithm uses 50% less CPU than the first algorithm shared. Besides using
more tokens, there is another catch. If you study the algorithm, you’ll notice
that crescent and hollow shaped objects will get filled instead of outlined.
The green arrow below would be the first algorithm, while the red arrow would
be this rectangle algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-child&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;/res/img/efficient_outline_moon.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture.&quot; class=&quot;rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to be using this in my
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alanxoc3/status/1086413617497423872&quot;&gt;Zeldo&lt;/a&gt; game in the
future, but I will probably go a step further and pre-process all the outlines,
so I don’t have to waste tokens for the code generating the outlines. That’s
all I wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="pico-8" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html">“How do I make a sprite have an outline in Pico-8?” I wondered. That question lead me to find this algorithm:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A brand new blog.</title><link href="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/24/a-brand-new-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A brand new blog." /><published>2019-06-24T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/24/a-brand-new-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://alanxoc3.github.io/2019/06/24/a-brand-new-blog.html">&lt;p class=&quot;center-child&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;/res/img/about_me_thinking.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A picture.&quot; class=&quot;rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;post-item&quot;&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;
      
If you have built castles in the air, your work need not be lost; that is where
they should be. Now put the foundations under them.

   &lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;cite class=&quot;quote-citation&quot;&gt;Henry David Thoreau&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi internet! It’s about time, I am finally starting my blog! I want to share
many of my life interests here. My posts will will vary between many different
things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the things I will definitely post about involve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Programming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PICO-8&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linux&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Piano&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mandarin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Music Composition&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Classic books&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interesting Experiences&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tutorials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hope with this blog is that something here will be helpful to you. Anyways,
see you soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="life" /><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>